Don Yoder collection of tape and disc recordings
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 2: Sound Recordings
  - Sound recording, April 28, 1979, RAA 46857; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:32:11, Side B: 00:32:09): analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, stereo; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR023)
    00:19:46 Elwood Cornett discusses the differences between the old and new ways of singing "Amazing Grace"
    00:21:27 church group, plus Charles Jones, perform "Amazing Grace" (described as the new way of singing it)
    00:22:45 church group, plus Charles Jones, perform "Amazing Grace" (described as the old way of singing it)
    n/a Elwood Cornett
    00:24:46 church group, plus Charles Jones, perform "On Jordan's Stormy Banks I Stand"
    00:26:37 church group, plus Charles Jones, perform a song (cut off by end of recording)
  - Sound recording, April 28, 1979, RAA 46858; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:28:38, Side B: 00:30:30): analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, stereo; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR024)
    Symposium on Rural Hymnody, held at Berea College, April 27-29, 1979. Session C: A Program of Gospel Hymnody by the Phipps Family (A.L., Kathleen, and Donna) of Barbourville, Kentucky. reel 2 of 2
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46859; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:23:46, Side B: 00:23:41): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR025)
    Barbara Olson interviews Aunt Fannie [sic] on powwowing, witches, and superstitions.
  - Sound recording, circa 1965, RAA 46860; 1 sound tape reel (00:12:49): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR026)
    According to accompanying documentation, this recording was for an assignment, so probably made by a student in one of Don Yoder's classes. An unidentified girl speaks (in Pennsylvania German). Several songs are introduced, then performed, including a song played on piano: "Eine Vina Violet" [?] (the choral version may be from another recording). A child can be heard speaking, at a distance from the microphone, at the end of the recording.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46861; 1 sound tape reel (00:33:08): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR027)
    The recording begins with an unidentified man talking about a record made by about 60 teenage boys and girls of the Shaker Village Work Group. They researched and recorded the songs as part of their work at the Shaker Village Project near Pittsfield, Massachusetts, in preserving Shaker cultural materials. He gives a history of Shakers in the U.S. The interview with Brother Ricardo Belden begins at 00:07:17 and ends at 00:14:48. The interviewer is probably Don Yoder. At 00:14:50, a man introduces and plays songs on the piano. The choral versions of songs that follow may be from the recording mentioned at the beginning of the tape. The recording speed becomes erratic at 00:30:23, and begins slowing down.
  - Sound recording, December 5 [no year given], RAA 46862; 1 sound tape reel (00:49:08): analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR028)
    Recording made at St. Luke and the Epiphany, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Interviews with Phyllis Brownell, Father [Rev.] Frederick R. Isacksen, Clay Gordon, and Clara V___ [?].
    This tape is copied from another recording. There are problems with the recording speed (possibly from the source tape). The audio cuts off abruptly at the end of the recording. The recording also includes what could be a recording of a radio broadcast of a church service; possibly led Rev. Billy Graham.
  - Sound recording, November 19, 1965, RAA 46863; 1 sound tape reel (Side A, part 1: 01:27:32, Side A, part 2: 00:38:48, Side B: 00:44:14): analog, 7 1/2 ips (Side A, part 1) and 3 3/4 (Side A, part 2 and Side B), half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR029)
    Digitization note: The source tape broke at two points. Fresh splice tape was used to reattach the tape. Sticky shed syndrome was evident at the beginning of the tape. It was baked to rectify the problem. Later during playback, the tape would suddenly come to a halt, but this was not a result of sticky shed syndrome. To correct the problem, the engineer, wearing white gloves, manually held the tape while it played, effectively acting as a brush. The digital file for Side A was divided into two files to compensate for the then-current WAV file size limitations.
    Church service. The recording begins with organ music. There were technical problems when the recording was created, with several instances of drop-out. Continued on SR029, Side A, part 2.
    Interview on spiritual healing. Carter W. Craigie interviews Dr. Amos Seldomridge, Collegeville, Pennsylvania, who talks about seminary, experience with spiritual healing, and the Church of the Heavenly Rest. Recorded in Collegeville, Pennsylvania.
  - Sound recording, November 6, 1971, RAA 46864; 1 sound tape reel (00:31:28): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR030)
    Don Yoder interviews folk artist Jennie Trein, tape 1 of 3. The date refers to the recording; the announcement was recorded on a later date. The recording begins with high-pitched squeaking/squealing. Don Yoder introduces the recording. Jennie C. Trein introduces herself, and during the interview recites the Lord's Prayer in German (or Pennsylvania German).
  - Sound recording, November 6, 1971, RAA 46865; 1 sound tape reel (00:32:42): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR031)
    Don Yoder interviews folk artist Jennie Trein, tape 2 of 3. The date refers to the recording; the announcement was recorded on a later date.
  - Sound recording, November 6, 1971, RAA 46866; 1 sound tape reel (00:29:59): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR032)
    Don Yoder interviews folk artist Jennie Trein, tape 3 of 3. The date refers to the recording; the announcement was recorded on a later date.
  - Sound recording, December 30, 1965, RAA 46867; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:27:37, Side B: 01:09:39): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR033)
    The recording was probably made for Yoder's Religious Thought class by one of his students (perhaps D. Frank).
    Digitization note: Low audio volume throughout the interview. A high-pitched squeal can be heard later in recording; some sound distortion as well.
    Interview on Jewish beliefs and practices. Mrs. Tebela (?), originally from Aleppo, is the interview subject. Subjects include amulets, use of the term "a kina hara" (Yiddish) more than once; possibly followed by some Hebrew later (b'ruch-ah). The audio volume is very low, and garbled at the beginning. See SR034, Side A, for similar subject content.
    Archivist's note: "kine hara" is actually "kein ayin hara" or literally "no evil eye," a saying meant to ward off bad luck).
    Interview on Jewish beliefs and practices. Mrs. Rachel Hanon (born Raquel Hanono; the interviewee) came from Aleppo in 1921; her father was a rabbi. The interview ends at 01:09:10.
  - Sound recording, December 30, 1965, RAA 46868; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:15:52, Side B: 00:35:33): analog, 7 1/2 ips (Side A) and 3 3/4 ips (Side B), half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR034)
    Interview on Jewish beliefs and practices; also, healing. Other people can be heard, helping the interview along; opera music can be heard in the background. An unidentified man (Don Yoder?) interviews Mrs. Gindhi. She came from Syria to U. S. 45 years ago. Later, the phrase "a kina hara" is used. See SR033, Side B for similar content.
    Interview concerns the customs and traditions of Syrian Jews. A woman can be heard, having discussion with the interview subject. Audio distortion early in recording. An unidentified man interviews Mrs. Safdeye. He says he studies customs and traditions of Syrian Jews in Brooklyn and Turkish Jews in Seattle, Washington, to see similarities. She says she came to US in 1943. Before that, she lived in England and in Columbia. Her family was from Aleppo (father was from Aleppo and mother from Nicocea). There are high-pitched sound towards end of recording; audio is cut off at tape's end.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46869; 1 sound tape reel (00:57:41): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR035)
    Probably a demonstration tape. Compilation of performances of various types of choral Christian music, performed by different groups. Some are accompanied, others a cappella. The recording includes an unidentified man preaching during an African American church service.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46870; 1 sound tape reel (00:45:18): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR036)
    Probably recorded at the Pennsylvania Dutch Folk Festival. An unidentified man is the announcer; participants include Paul Brumbach and Mabel Snyder, and Rev. Brumbach's son. Unidentified event where Pennsylvania Dutch funeral customs and lore are discussed, including horse and buggy funeral customs. Audio ends at 00:45:08.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46871; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:32:26, Side B: 00:13:20): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR037)
    Probably recorded at the Pennsylvania Dutch Folk Festival. Pennsylvania Dutch funeral customs are discussed. Duplicate of an earlier section of SR036.
    Probably recorded at the Pennsylvania Dutch Folk Festival. Pennsylvania Dutch funeral customs are discussed. Duplicate of the latter section of SR036.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46872; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:14:55, Side B: 00:17:09): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR038)
    This may be a dubbed copy of a commercial recording. The tape container says "Harlem congregation" and also "London (English) Records."
    African American religious service. Audio begins at 00:00:04, with an unidentified male speaker and voices of the congregation. Recording also includes the congregation singing.
    African American religious service. Audio begins at 00:00:05. Recording includes the congregation singing, with organ accompaniment. Audio ends at 00:17:03.
  - Sound recording, 1962-1966, RAA 46873; 1 sound tape reel (00:46:38): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR039)
    African American religious singing (both in services and outside services), and at end, secular singing ("Stewball"). Much distortion and a ground hum later in the recording.
    The recording was sent to Don Yoder by Marian P. Michael, acoompanied by a letter dated December 19, 1968. The tape is a compilation of recordings Michael originally recorded, meant to reflect typical Texas African American services; see Marian P. Michael collection of Texas Baptist hymns and services (AFC 1980/033). See the tape container image for a complete list of songs, performers, dates, and locations.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46874; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 01:04:24, Side B: 00:04:47): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR040)
    Written on the tape container: "Demonstration tape to accompany 'A Selected and Annotated Discography of American Negro Religious Music on Commercially Manufactured Records, Designed to Illustrate Varieties of Instrumental and Vocal Combinations'" -- David J. Winslow, 1967
    Compilation of African American blues singing, jazz, and possibly folk.
    African American gospel singing. May be dubbed from another recording; fades out towards the end.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46875; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:19:57, Side B: 00:19:57): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 4 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR041)
    Compilation tape of African American gospel and secular singing, some performances possibly recorded live, and others prerecorded. The audio on Side B begins in fits and starts.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46876; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:23:17, Side B: 00:23:12): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 4 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR042)
    Compilation of recordings of religious songs, plus at least one jazz instrumental song, an African song, a song with (perhaps) a kettle drum and other percussion; seems to be a percussion-oriented compilation tape, created for a classroom assignment by Richard Raichelson.
    A group performs a song (Possibly Native American, followed by instrumental performances: Jew's harp, kazoo, flute, and harmonica.
    Compilation tape of recordings of African American and (perhaps) African song, both vocal and instrumental.
  - Sound recording, April-May 1967, RAA 46877; 1 sound tape reel (00:10:40): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR043)
    Interview on African American religious services; two other singers after the interview.
    00:00:01 unidentified woman (interviewer) speaks about emotion and songs, and camp meetings
    00:00:22 Lacey Hall (60 years old) tells of Oriole Camp Meeting and African American singing (his ideas).
    00:06:10 Mrs. Ella Talley (76 years), talks about the Brandywine Summit Camp Meeting, and sings "Give Me That Old-Time Religion"
    00:07:07 Mrs. Ella Talley sings "Gospel Medley"
    00:08:48 Rev. Milton Keene, Seaford, DE; 60 years old, sings "Telephone to Glory"
    00:09:13 Life is Like a Mountain Railway" (song), possibly performed by Rev. Keene
    00:10:08 "We Will Roll the Old Chariot Along" (song), possibly performed by Rev. Keene
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46878; 1 sound tape reel (00:30:30): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR044)
    Program of bush meeting songs/revival meetings; see SR006, Side B. Low-quality audio.
    00:00:04 Don Yoder introduces the part of the program with lining out of German hymns in the churches of Pennsylvania
    00:01:40 Clarence Kulp and Rein Gottshall, Montgomery County, Pennsylvania, perform lined-out singing
    00:06:38 Don Yoder speaks about 18th-century style; invasion of Methodist preachers; history of different churches descended from these activities; the following is an example of the "shouting Dutch" (bush meeting singing style)
    00:09:04 Jim Miller; Lanceton (?) Menser (his father is Harry Menser), Lykens Valley; an introduction, followed by singing
    00:12:38 Don Yoder introduces William Yeakel
    00:13:40 William Yeakel and Clarence Kulp sing "Ich Wil Himmel Bleiben Drei..." [?]
    00:14:15 Don Yoder follows their song with an explanation of the song and its context, and then introduces WIlliam Yeakel again to sing a song about the land of milk and honey
    00:15:08 Don Yoder follows their song with an explanation of the song and its context, and then introduces William Yeakel again to sing a song about the land of milk and honey. Clarence Kulp joins Yeakel in singing the song.
    00:16:23 Don Yoder introduces the Lykens Valley Bush Meeting Singers again
    00:17:07 "When the Roll Is Called Up Yonder" (sung in Pennsylvania German)
    00:18:58 following an announcement of the titles for the next two songs, the singers perform the next song ("How Happy We'll Be Over in Heaven," in Pennsylvania German)
    00:19:58 the singers perform "Singet Hallelujah"
    00:21:03 Don Yoder speaks about the previous song, and introduces the next song ("the old battle chorus")
    00:21:28 the group performs the song
    00:23:13 Don Yoder has William Yeakel sing a slightly different version of the same song
    00:23:30 William Yeakel sings the "embellished version" of the song
    00:24:15 Don Yoder introduces William Yeakel to sing again, with John Moyer joining him
    00:24:39 "Will the Pearly Gates Stand Open Always" (in Pennsylvania German)
    00:25:42 Don Yoder calls on the Lykens Valley singers to perform the next song
    00:25:55 the group sings a song in Pennsylvania German
    00:27:08 Don Yoder introduces a farewell hymn, and asks Lanceton Menser, Jim Miller, and their Lykens Valley Bush Meeting Singers to perform it
    00:28:13 the group performs the song
    00:29:29 audio lapse; followed by other noises and audio problems
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46879; 1 sound tape reel (Part 1: 00:00:53, Part 2: 00:32:25): analog, 3 3/4 ips (Part 1) and 7 1/2 ips (Part 2), full track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR045)
    The source tape was recorded at two speeds: 3 3/4 ips for the introduction, and 7 1/2 ips for the balance of the tape. Two digital files of one side were created as a result.
    Part 1
    Religious service (introduction).
    Part 2
    Religious service. African American religious beliefs, laying on of hands, healing. The recording includes an interview with an unidentified woman, possibly interviewed by Don Yoder.
  - Sound recording, circa 1958, RAA 46880; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:32:05, Side B: 00:18:19): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR046)
    Jehovah's Witnesses. An unidentified woman interviews Miss Frost and Mr. Carrick. Part of the interview includes information about when each was "dedicated."
    Seventh-Day Adventists. The same interviewer heard on SR046, Side A, here interviews Mrs. Cox.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46881; 1 sound tape reel (Side A, version 1: 01:15:40, Side A, version 2: 00:04:39, Side A, version 3: 01:15:41, Side B, version 1: 00:48:08, Side B, version 2: 00:48:02): analog, 3 3/4 ips (Side A, versions 1 and 3 and Side B, version 1) and 7 1/2 ips (Side A, version 2 and Side B, version 2), half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR047)
    Side A, version 1
    Don Yoder (?) interviews Dr. Alfred W. Price. Music has been recorded over the interview, so both music and talk can be heard, but the talk is almost inaudible. At 00:42:45 the crosstalk ends, and the interview can be heard clearly, with no music. At 01:06:03, the speaking voice can be heard at very slow speed.
    Side A, version 2
    Two men discuss setting up recording equipment. This is a segment from SR047, Side A, part 1 that sounds slowed down. Due to fluctuating recordings speeds on Side A of the source tape, this part of the recording was digitized at 7 1/2 ips, in order to capture the section recorded at a different speed.
    Side A, version 3
    An unidentified man, who is Episcopalian and from Richmond, Virginia, interviews another man on the topic of spiritual healing. Due to fluctuating recording speeds on Side A of the source tape, this part of the recording was digitized at 3 3/4 ips, on one-half track.
    Side B, versions 1 and 2
    Compilation of recordings of African American and folk music; some religious. The recording begins with prerecorded music ("Stewball"); see SR039. At 00:09:55 is a recording of the Weavers singing "Born in Bethlehem." Due to fluctuating recordings speeds on Side B of the source tape, this part of the recording was transferred at 7 1/2 ips. Effectively, the two version of Side B are the same recording, except version 1 is longer, and at a lower volume.
  - Sound recording, 1971 or before, RAA 46882; 1 sound tape reel (00:29:13): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR048)
    An unidentified woman interviews Rev. Alfred W. Price, St. Stephen's Protestant Episcopal Church, on the subject of faith healing. Several voices can be heard early in the recording.
  - Sound recording, April 30, 1977, RAA 46883; 1 sound tape reel (00:32:07): analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR049)
    Several voices can be heard speaking and singing during a religious service (including sacred harp singing). Distortion at the end of the recording. This is a copy of the original recording.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46884; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:29:28, Side B: 00:28:31): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR050)
    This tape was dubbed from sound discs, and includes religious music. Side B ends at 00:05:03; the rest of the tape has no audio. The tape box suggests this recording was made by Joe D. Boyd for Yoder's Folklore 622 class.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46885; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:28:55, Side B: 00:32:02): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR051)
    According to the tape box, the tape contents focus on American folk hymnody, and is a "demonstration tape (Archie Green)."
    Compilation of songs that were (probably) prerecorded. An unidentified man sings "Wash in that Beautiful Pool" and "The Cowboy's Dream" [?] (to the tune of "My Bonnie Lies Over the Ocean").
    Compilation of prerecorded songs (some are sacred harp songs). Program includes "Come, Come Ye Saints" (Mormon song), "Hick's Farewell" (performed by Doc Watson), and "Shall We Gather at the River."
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46886; 1 sound tape reel (01:08:27): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR052)
    Samuel Meyers is interviewed by his granddaughter on Jewish beliefs and practices. Instances of low audio and audio dropout; the audio cuts off abruptly at the end of the recording.
  - Sound recording, 1961, RAA 46887; 1 sound tape reel (01:00:53): analog, 1 7/8 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR053)
    Interview on Jewish beliefs and practices. First part of audio is absent (a problem from the source recording). Much of the audio volume is low. The interview subject may be Mr. Weiss (from Elizabeth, New Jersey).
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46888; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:32:18, Side B: 00:32:22): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR054)
    A compilation of country songs, performed live. Instruments include banjo, guitar, and accordion; some vocals can be heard. Audio cuts off abruptly at the end of the recording on both tape sides.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46889; 1 sound tape reel (00:31:13): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR055)
    A compilation of songs, including Harry R. Gwire (?).
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46890; 1 sound tape reel (00:32:34): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR056)
    A church service (?), conducted in Pennsylvania German, with songs and spoken- word passages. The audio is sometimes very low, and cuts off abruptly at the end of the recording.
  - Sound recording, 1961, RAA 46891; 1 sound tape reel (00:30:00): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR057)
    Religious songs in Pennsylvania German. Don Yoder [?] may be heard speaking at intervals. At 00:08:24 Mrs. Allan Baylor [?] sings a table grace. The audio cuts off abruptly at the end of the recording. According to notes accompanying the tape box, John Moyer, Mrs. Gottshall, and Clayton Bixler are on the recording.
  - Sound recording, July 1951, RAA 46892; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:28:01, Side B: 00:28:51): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR058)
    2nd Annual Pennsylvania Dutch Folk Festival, Kutztown, Pennsylvania; telecast by WEEU radio. Don Yoder gives religious history (including Methodist) of the area; see SR006, Side B. A long screech occurs towards end of recording.
    2nd Annual Pennsylvania Dutch Folk Festival, Kutztown, Pennsylvania; telecast by WEEU radio. This seems to be the same recording as SR058, Side A, except with a final announcement.
  - Sound recording, March 12, 1961, RAA 46893; 1 sound tape reel (00:33:07): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR059)
    Clarence Wagner (born January 2, 1879) sings spirituals in Pennsylvania German; there are other voices heard as well. Recorded by Don Yoder in Annville, Pennsylvania. This tape is a copy of the original recording. The audio cuts off abruptly at the end of the recording.